
[
    {
       "question": "Neo4j is ... DB",
       "options": ["relational", "NoSQL"],
       "correct_answer": "NoSQL"
     },
     {
      "question": "Big Data and real-time web applications ...",
      "options": ["NoSQL", "SQL"],
      "correct_answer": "NoSQL"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the difference between Hudson and Jenkins?",
      "options": ["Who are these people?", "No difference, Hudson is former name of Jenkins"],
      "correct_answer": "No difference, Hudson is former name of Jenkins"
    },
    {
      "question": "HTML: Every page contains: ... and ... ",
      "options": ["head, body", "head, tail", "doctype, body"],
      "correct_answer": "head, body"
    },
    {
      "question": "... adds styles to HTML",
      "options": ["JSON", "CSS"],
      "correct_answer": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Styles, Borders, Fonts, Sizes, Colors, Background are related to ... ",
      "options": ["CSS", "HTML"],
      "correct_answer": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "CSS: ....  this is when each element is represented as a rectangular box",
      "options": ["Box Model", "Flexbox Model", "Grid"],
      "correct_answer": "Box Model"
    },
    {
      "question": ".. is the most commonly used framework for Front-End-Development",
      "options": ["Django", "Bootstrap"],
      "correct_answer": "Bootstrap"
    },
    {
      "question": "To layout web application on multiple screen sizes, laptop, desktop, mobile etc we need ...",
      "options": ["Grid system", "Screen", "Electricity"],
      "correct_answer": "Grid system"
    },
    {
      "question": "In web design, a ... is a large, prominent section typically used to grab attention on a webpage. ",
      "options": ["jumbotron", "spider man"],
      "correct_answer": "jumbotron"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Bootstrap 5, the jumbotron class was removed",
      "options": ["yes", "no"],
      "correct_answer": "yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "document.URL, document.body, document.head, document.links are important attributes of ...",
      "options": ["DOM", "CSS", "HTML5"],
      "correct_answer": "DOM"
    },
    {
      "question": "A ... is a distributed network of servers strategically located across various geographic regions to deliver web content to users more efficiently and quickly",
      "options": ["CDN", "Youtube"],
      "correct_answer": "CDN"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: a variable can be reassigned to different types of values without any explicit type declaration",
      "options": ["yes", "no"],
      "correct_answer": "yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Using ...  for naming variables, functions, and other identifiers in Python is a standard convention that improves readability and consistency in your code",
      "options": ["snake_case", "rabbit_case", "chameleon_case"],
      "correct_answer": "snake_case"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: ... are implemented using hash tables, which provide very efficient lookups, insertions, and deletions",
      "options": ["Dictionaries", "Lists", "Nested Lists"],
      "correct_answer": "Dictionaries"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: Sets allow duplicate values and are ordered",
      "options": ["do not allow and are unordered", "allow and ordered", "allow and unordered"],
      "correct_answer": "do not allow and are unordered"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: f-strings provide a way to embed expressions inside string literals, using ...",
      "options": ["{}", "()", "[]"],
      "correct_answer": "{}"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: .... functions are small, anonymous functions that can have any number of arguments but can only have one expression",
      "options": ["Beta", "Lambda", "Alpha", "Alpha Numeric"],
      "correct_answer": "Lambda"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: Lambda functions are useful for creating ..., one-time-use functions",
      "options": ["quick", "heavy"],
      "correct_answer": "quick"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: This my_list[2:6] is example of ... ",
      "options": ["Slicing Notation", "Chunking Notation", "It is not Python syntax"],
      "correct_answer": "Slicing Notation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: The ... statement creates a context manager that handles the opening and closing of the file",
      "options": ["there are two statements: fopen and fclose", "with"],
      "correct_answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: The ... function in Python is used to get an index and the value from an iterable simultaneously during a loop",
      "options": ["enumerate()", "zip()"],
      "correct_answer": "enumerate()"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: ...  are special functions that use the 'yield' keyword instead of 'return'",
      "options": ["Downshifts", "Generators"],
      "correct_answer": "Generators"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: ... in Python are used to create isolated spaces for different projects, ensuring that dependencies for one project do not affect another",
      "options": ["Sand Box", "Virtual environments", "Test Bed"],
      "correct_answer": "Virtual environments"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: The __...__ file is essential for creating a Python package. It signals to Python that the directory should be treated as a package, allowing you to import modules from it",
      "options": ["package.py", "init.py", "npm.py"],
      "correct_answer": "init.py"
    },
    {
      "question": "In programming, an ... is a common pattern or practice that is widely used and accepted by developers in that language",
      "options": ["idiom", "proverb", "rule"],
      "correct_answer": "idiom"
    },
    {
      "question": "Python: This if __name__ == '__main__':  is ...",
      "options": ["bad code example", "idiom"],
      "correct_answer": "idiom"
    },
    {
      "question": "Google originated by ...",
      "options": ["it is an abstract name", "googol", "no one knows"],
      "correct_answer": "googol"
    },
    {
      "question": "SQLite DB is serverless",
      "options": ["yes", "no"],
      "correct_answer": "yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "ML: ... or learning to learn, is the science of systematically observing how different machine learning approaches perform on a wide range of learning tasks, and then learning from this experience, or meta-data, to learn new tasks much faster than otherwise possible",
      "options": ["Meta-learning", "Generative AI", "Reinforcement Learning"],
      "correct_answer": "Meta-learning"
    },
    {
      "question": "ML: Transfer learning is commonly used in many ... tasks",
      "options": ["computer vision", "NLP", "sentiment analysis"],
      "correct_answer": "computer vision"
    },
    {
      "question": "ML: ...  involves updating the weights of some or all layers of the pre-trained model to adapt it to the new task",
      "options": ["Fine-tuning", "Transfer learning"],
      "correct_answer": "Fine-tuning"
    },
    {
      "question": "ML: ... smartly addresses this challenge of training ML models on private data",
      "options": ["Federated learning", "Incognito Learning", "Against the law Learning"],
      "correct_answer": "Federated learning"
    },
    {
      "question": "ML: We want our model to take a real value (x) as input and generate two outputs: cos(x), sin(x), it is an example of ...",
      "options": ["It is Federated Learning definitely", "This can be formulated as a multitasking problem"],
      "correct_answer": "This can be formulated as a multitasking problem"
    }
]

   